Becca King

TITLE

Web Developer + Writer

CONTACT

216-570-0627 rebecca.lynne.king@gmail.com Cleveland, OH 44102

WEBSITE

rebeccaking.info

SKILLS

JavaScript
HTML
CSS
CSS Preprocessors (i.e. Less)
Git version control
jQuery
SQL
Progress OpenEdge
WordPress
React (introductory)
Journalism
Nonfiction Writing

EDUCATION

Blogging

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive, project-based program in full stack web

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a full stack web developer and a nonfiction writer. I am passionate about creating accessible online experiences for diverse populations, and I believe that responsive design is key to creating a more usable Internet. I work closely with design professionals, information technologists, and editors to bring visions to life.

EXPERIENCE

Amerimark Direct, LLC, Web Developer

Middleburg Heights, OH - Nov 2020 - Current

- Developed front and back end solutions based on design specifications and information technology needs, working alongside diverse teams towards common goals.
- Researched and implemented practical solutions to accessibility problems on our sites.
- Primary front-end specialist on a team of web developers.
- Completed training in React and web accessibility.

We Write Blog Posts, Ghostwriter

Jul 2020 - Current

- Completed exhaustive research on diverse topics to build information for accurate writing.
- Adapted tone and wording choice to successfully connect with different target audiences.
- Reviewed work in detail to correct factual errors and grammatical problems.

North Coast Media, Web Developer

Cleveland, OH - Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Full stack development of websites based on a WordPress CMS.
- Technologies used include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, WordPress, PHP, SQL, Google Tag Manager.

development. Independent and collaborative learning in JavaScript, jQuery, React, Angular, SQL, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, PHP, and Git version control.

Miami University
Bachelor of Science
Kinesiology
Environmental Science
University Honors Program

• Developed websites to work properly across multiple browsers, including those created by Microsoft, Google, and Mozilla.

Freelance, Magazine Writer

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

- Wrote articles for Teen Vogue and LGBTQ Nation.
- Used appropriate voice tones and diction to compose engaging content for audiences of various ages.
- Produced creative and error-free content by applying outstanding writing and editing skills.
- Maintained updated understanding of writing industry and genre trends to strengthen writing success and marketability.

Ohio University, Graduate Assistant in Journalism

Athens, OH - Aug 2017 - May 2019

- Created and maintained digital media platforms.
- Learned about the principles of online journalism as they apply to the fields of medicine and environmental science.

Freelance, News Writer

Athens, Ohio - Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- Researched news story information through trusted sources and verified facts before publishing.
- Wrote exciting, captivating, and authentic pieces to engage audience members.
- Generated original story ideas, developed fresh perspectives, and oversaw story development from inception to completion.

Americorps - La Puente Shelter, Community Educator and Volunteer Coordinator

Alamosa, CO - Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

- Developed, prepared, and presented program information to guide awareness, share findings, and build community relationships.
- Introduced to Adobe Photoshop and Indesign through training with a professional graphic designer.